<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Leo Robinovitch @ The Leo Zone</title><link>https://theleo.zone/</link><description>Recent content on Leo Robinovitch @ The Leo Zone</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://theleo.zone/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Book Review: The Scout Mindset</title><link>https://theleo.zone/books/the-scout-mindset/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/books/the-scout-mindset/</guid><description>Rating:🧠
The Scout Mindset is a book by Julia Galef. It introduces the concept of &amp;ldquo;Scout mindset&amp;rdquo;, contrasted with &amp;ldquo;Soldier mindset&amp;rdquo;. A Soldier mindset is present when our unconscious motives affect the conclusions we draw. A Scout seeks to continually align their perceptions closer to reality.
If directionally motivated reasoning is like being a soldier fighting off threatening evidence, accuracy motivated reasoning is like being a scout forming a map of the strategic landscape.</description></item><item><title>Book Review: The Murderbot Diaries</title><link>https://theleo.zone/books/murderbot/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/books/murderbot/</guid><description>Rating:🫨
The Murderbot Diaries is a series by Martha Wells. I would say it is in the Sci-Fi genre but also teen angst and also whatever genre the movie Gladiator is in.
To preface this review, I have only read the first 3 novels in this series (there are 7 books at the time of this writing). I also read this in an extremely busy period of life where I would read 1-3 pages at a time at night before falling asleep.</description></item><item><title>unhealthy database migrations</title><link>https://theleo.zone/posts/unhealthy-db-migrations/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/posts/unhealthy-db-migrations/</guid><description>Often, integration tests follow this pattern:
Stand up a docker database container Run migrations against this database container Run the integration tests against this migrated container This can be done with docker compose as follows, using Postgres and goose as an example:
./docker-compose.yaml
services: postgres: image: postgres:latest environment: POSTGRES_USER: leo POSTGRES_PASSWORD: 123 POSTGRES_DB: db ports: - &amp;#34;5432:5432&amp;#34; healthcheck: test: [&amp;#34;CMD-SHELL&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;pg_isready&amp;#34;] interval: 1s postgres-migrations: build: context: . dockerfile: Dockerfile-goose volumes: - .</description></item><item><title>the machine</title><link>https://theleo.zone/posts/the-machine/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/posts/the-machine/</guid><description>It is your first day at the Machine.
Your new machinemate, a Machinist who has been stationed here for a long time and designed and constructed much of the Machine themselves, brings you towards it.
The Machine mostly looks like the others you&amp;rsquo;ve worked on: a large wall, full of buttons and dials and knobs and readouts and flashing indicators. This one must be five stories tall. There&amp;rsquo;s about a sports field&amp;rsquo;s worth of it to your left and right, and no guessing its depth.</description></item><item><title>Book Review: The Mindbody Prescription: Healing the Body, Healing the Pain</title><link>https://theleo.zone/books/the-mind-body-prescription/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/books/the-mind-body-prescription/</guid><description>Rating: 💊
The Mindbody Prescription: Healing the Body, Healing the Pain is a book by John Sarno, a doctor and author who was known for coining Tension Myositis Syndrome (TMS), a condition that manifests as many different forms of chronic pain.
I had heard the name Sarno in internet conversations around back pain, but he came up again when I was talking with a friend about my typing pain and he mentioned that he had read a kind of wacky book (this one) about pain treatment when he was experiencing the same thing and his pain went away after reading it and he never thinks about it anymore.</description></item><item><title>pdf-ify a website</title><link>https://theleo.zone/posts/pdf-ify-a-website/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/posts/pdf-ify-a-website/</guid><description>I love writing a bit of code at the airport gate. My flight today had a 45 minute delay, so I was able to slap together a solution to a small problem I had.
I recently got a reMarkable 2 and love it. I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading through SICP on it, and really enjoy inserting note pages inline to do the exercises while I read the text.
I want to reference solutions for SICP problems to check my own answers and for when I get stuck.</description></item><item><title>a visit to Bletchley Park</title><link>https://theleo.zone/posts/a-visit-to-bletchley-park/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/posts/a-visit-to-bletchley-park/</guid><description>I cannot imagine how, with our primitive methods of collecting and registering traffic, and our tiny staff for decoding it, we managed to cope at all. The main sensation of the newcomer was that he was participating in a miracle which he was entirely incapable of comprehending.
- Stuart Milner-Barry, Codebreaker at Bletchley Park
One of my highest priority trips while living in London this year was visiting Bletchley Park.</description></item><item><title>Book Review: The Devil in the White City</title><link>https://theleo.zone/books/the-devil-in-the-white-city/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/books/the-devil-in-the-white-city/</guid><description>Rating: 👹
The Devil in the White City is a book by Erik Larson about the 1893 World&amp;rsquo;s Columbian Exposition (&amp;ldquo;the fair&amp;rdquo;) in Chicago. It follows two main characters: Daniel Burnham, the fair&amp;rsquo;s primary architect, and H. H. Holmes, a serial killer who operated during the time of the fair.
I&amp;rsquo;m a bit late to the party on this one. It was big after it came out in 2003, and my mom recommended it to me at least 5 years ago, but 2023 seems like my year of Chicago - watching The Bear, putting together that something like 20% of my friends are from Chicago, and now this book.</description></item><item><title>customizing the Glove80 keyboard with ZMK</title><link>https://theleo.zone/posts/configuring-glove80/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/posts/configuring-glove80/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve recently been dealing with some wrist/hand/forearm pain from typing. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried a few different ergonomic keyboards to see if any of them help, and they definitely have! Some reviews in brief:
ZSA Moonlander: ortholinear layout, split halves, tentable, palm rests, but still did not feel very ergo to me. Felt like I was often stretching my hands quite a bit and the thumb cluster felt uncomfortably spaced. I enjoyed customizing it, but the keyboard itself wasn&amp;rsquo;t friendly for my hands.</description></item><item><title>Book Review: Unreasonable Hospitality</title><link>https://theleo.zone/books/unreasonable-hospitality/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/books/unreasonable-hospitality/</guid><description>Rating: 🧑‍🍳💋
Unreasonable Hospitality is a book by Will Guidara about his experience in the restaurant industry. In particular, he writes about managing Eleven Madison Park (EMP) for 11 years, taking it from a &amp;ldquo;mere&amp;rdquo; 2 stars to being awarded the prize of best restaurant in the world.
Guidara is the first to call out the silliness and practical importance of this award:
&amp;hellip;it’s absolutely ridiculous to call any restaurant “the best restaurant in the world.</description></item><item><title>Book Review: Designing Data Intensive Applications</title><link>https://theleo.zone/books/designing-data-intensive-applications/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/books/designing-data-intensive-applications/</guid><description>Rating: 📀
Designing Data Intensive Applications (DDIA) is a book by Martin Kleppmann.
How do I review this incredible reference? I&amp;rsquo;ll first say that if you program professionally, you should read this book. It will introduce you to new ideas and help you clarify and reconceptualize ones you may already be familiar with. You are very likely to find relevance to your work in multiple chapters. You can view my abridged notes in Notion here if you&amp;rsquo;d like.</description></item><item><title>Book Review: Tomorrow, and Tomorrow, and Tomorrow</title><link>https://theleo.zone/books/tomorrow-and-tomorrow-and-tomorrow/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/books/tomorrow-and-tomorrow-and-tomorrow/</guid><description>Rating:👾
Tomorrow, and Tomorrow, and Tomorrow (T3) is a novel by Gabrielle Zevin.
I really enjoyed this book, ripping through it on my flight and subsequent jetlagged morning as I move back from London to the West Coast. Spoilers ahead.
Many people I know have read and enjoyed this book in the past months. Zevin mentions some influences in her author&amp;rsquo;s note at the end, and summarizes that the book is about Work and it is about Love, and that struck me as a good summary.</description></item><item><title>Book Review: The Light of All That Falls</title><link>https://theleo.zone/books/the-light-of-all-that-falls/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/books/the-light-of-all-that-falls/</guid><description>Rating:🔦
The Light of All That Falls is the third and final book in The Licanius Trilogy, a fantasy series by James Islington.
The book nicely rounds out this excellent series. Spoilers ahead.
This series really emphasizes that everyone thinks that they are doing what is best for the world. Aarkein Devaed and the Venerate believed that releasing &amp;ldquo;El&amp;rdquo; is the way to grant people freedom of choice and undo the harms of the past.</description></item><item><title>Book Review: An Echo of Things to Come</title><link>https://theleo.zone/books/an-echo-of-things-to-come/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/books/an-echo-of-things-to-come/</guid><description>Rating:🗼
An Echo of Things to Come is the second book in The Licanius Trilogy, a fantasy series by James Islington.
I enjoyed the second book here even more than the first. As usual, spoilers ahead.
The first book left a large volume of unexplained content, and at first, it seemed like that was just going to grow throughout the second book. I was worried, becausing explaining all of it in the trilogy&amp;rsquo;s finale would be pretty ambitious.</description></item><item><title>Book Review: The Shadow of What Was Lost</title><link>https://theleo.zone/books/the-shadow-of-what-was-lost/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/books/the-shadow-of-what-was-lost/</guid><description>Rating: 🪄
The Shadow of What Was Lost is the first book in The Licanius Trilogy, a fantasy series by James Islington.
I really enjoyed this book. As usual, spoilers ahead.
The setting in this book feels huge. It&amp;rsquo;s like a Marvel Movie in High fantasy format, seriously, it&amp;rsquo;s a super hero book more than a fantasy book. In Brandon Sanderson&amp;rsquo;s worlds, he introduces a structured magical mechanic that influences physics or physical abilities, like the Allomantic metals in Mistborn or the Stormlight in The Stormlight Archive.</description></item><item><title>a simple hash table in C</title><link>https://theleo.zone/posts/hashmap-in-c/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/posts/hashmap-in-c/</guid><description>I implemented a simple hash table in C when solving a problem in CS Primer. Solving it helped me gain better intuition around hash functions, pointers, and memory segments like the stack and the heap.
Basics You have probably encountered a hash table in the wild, like a dict in Python, map in Go, or Map in JavaScript. Hash tables associate a key with a value. Setting, looking up, and deleting values is average O(1) time complexity &amp;ndash; fast.</description></item><item><title>Book Review: The Diamond Age</title><link>https://theleo.zone/books/the-diamond-age/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/books/the-diamond-age/</guid><description>Rating: 👎
Heavily opinionated claims and spoilers ahead.
I did not enjoy and do not recommend The Diamond Age, by Neil Stephenson. It was a particularly disappointing read for me because of how much I enjoyed Snow Crash last month.
The Diamond Age should be called The Rough (Unpolished) Diamond, as this could have been a great book. Imagining what a post-scarcity world full of accessible nanotechnology and universal 3D &amp;ldquo;matter printers&amp;rdquo; looks like is cool!</description></item><item><title>Book Review: Snow Crash</title><link>https://theleo.zone/books/snow-crash/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/books/snow-crash/</guid><description>Rating: ❄️📉
My experiences took on a different texture while I read Snow Crash by Neal Stephenson. The hyper-privatized, segmented-but-uniform world in which the plot unfolds gave me greater than usual mistrust for every McDonalds, gated community, and Airport shopping corridor.
As usual, spoilers ahead.
I loved the characters in Snow Crash. A mutant Aleut killer who uses glass knives and has a Hydrogen bomb synced to go off if he&amp;rsquo;s killed.</description></item><item><title>Book Review: The Scholomance Series</title><link>https://theleo.zone/books/the-scholomance-series/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/books/the-scholomance-series/</guid><description>Rating: 🧙‍♀️
If you enjoyed Harry Potter, The Magicians by Lev Grossman, or Game of Thrones, then you will probably have a great time with The Scholomance Series by Naomi Novik.
Warning: spoilers ahead.
The trilogy starts with the pedal to the metal. Soul sucking monsters, heroism, and drama in a boarding school for magical teens.
At first it felt like I was reading the journal of an overly melodramatic teenage girl, El.</description></item><item><title>Book Review: The Art of Learning</title><link>https://theleo.zone/books/the-art-of-learning/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/books/the-art-of-learning/</guid><description>Rating: 📈
A self help book usually acts like a manual for achieving above-average levels of success, wealth, positive mental state, etc., told through parables of the author&amp;rsquo;s life.
What qualities do we find distasteful in self help books?
taking it as a given that everyone should uncritically strive to dominate and win within a conventional framework of success claims that you, yes you, can dominate, win, and succeed like the author if you just follow these steps encouraging exploitation of others in order to win pushing pseudoscience, a la &amp;ldquo;Scientists hate this one simple trick&amp;rdquo; (positive thinking, law of attraction, etc.</description></item><item><title>how to only torrent through a vpn</title><link>https://theleo.zone/posts/torrent-through-vpn/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/posts/torrent-through-vpn/</guid><description>How can you make sure that you never accidentally have your torrent client on but your VPN off? You can restrict the network interface that your torrent client uses to that of your VPN.
To ensure privacy while torrenting legal content, you&amp;rsquo;ve probably heard the endless ads on podcasts and Youtube for using a VPN. This article assumes you already have a VPN and know how to turn it on and off.</description></item><item><title>Book Review: The Code Book</title><link>https://theleo.zone/books/the-code-book/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/books/the-code-book/</guid><description>Rating: 🧨
I picked up The Code Book at a used book store in Seattle, honestly expecting it to be a nonstarter. Another book on an interesting technical topic that assumes the reader has a PhD in the field or that they&amp;rsquo;d shrivel up at the first whiff of math.
I am happy to report that I was wrong! This is the best book I&amp;rsquo;ve read in the last year.</description></item><item><title>the linux upskill challenge</title><link>https://theleo.zone/posts/linux-upskill/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/posts/linux-upskill/</guid><description>The Linux Upskill Challenge is something I&amp;rsquo;ve been following on Reddit for a while and have been wanting to do. At this point, I&amp;rsquo;m pretty OK with computers, but I&amp;rsquo;d like to (re)learn some fundamentals of Linux and Unix systems.
This post contains my notes as I underwent the process.
Day 0: Setup Link
They recommend provisioning a VPC somewhere in the cloud. I chose AWS - signed up a for a new account on the free tier and created a t2.</description></item><item><title>reflecting on advent of code 2022</title><link>https://theleo.zone/posts/aoc-2022/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/posts/aoc-2022/</guid><description>WARNING: as per title, here be spoilers for Advent of Code 2022.
Advent of Code (AoC) is a set of puzzles released daily from Dec 1st through Dec 25th each year. Each puzzle has two parts, with the prize of a &amp;ldquo;star&amp;rdquo; for each part completed. Puzzles are solved with a computer program of your own creation.
My overall experience with AoC 2022 was better than it was last year. I had less needless stress and gained more practice, insight, and knowledge from each puzzle.</description></item><item><title>please, may i see my knee?</title><link>https://theleo.zone/posts/please-may-i-see-my-knee/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/posts/please-may-i-see-my-knee/</guid><description>TL;DR it can be hard to obtain, view, and share medical images of your own body. Scroll down for a cool video of the inside of my knee derived from a CD with DICON images on it uploaded to a cool open source viewer.
I have had persistent and increasing knee pain in my left knee for about five years. It&amp;rsquo;s a real bummer. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to get it fixed various times:</description></item><item><title>iterable[str] in python</title><link>https://theleo.zone/posts/mypy-iterable-str/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/posts/mypy-iterable-str/</guid><description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a fun thing with Python&amp;rsquo;s type annotations.
Sometimes one might use Iterable as a type annotation to try to indicate something might be a set, a list, or a tuple.
But Iterable really just means something that implements __iter__().
And str implements __iter__(), e.g.:
for char in &amp;#34;abc&amp;#34;: print(char) # a # b # c And &amp;ldquo;a&amp;rdquo; is a str, just like &amp;ldquo;abc&amp;rdquo; is a str.
So this type checks: my_var: Iterable[str] = &amp;quot;abc&amp;quot; (!</description></item><item><title>migrating kafka to amazon msk</title><link>https://theleo.zone/posts/migrating-to-msk/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/posts/migrating-to-msk/</guid><description>I work on the software team at Voltus. We orchestrate distributed energy resources-large-scale electricity users, residential consumers, batteries, and generators-to make the electric grid more resilient and pay our customers well.
This is the story of migrating one hundred microservices from self-managed Kafka in Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (Amazon EC2) to Amazon Managed Streaming for Apache Kafka (Amazon MSK).
Initial State Kafka was introduced to the Voltus tech stack in 2019 and quickly became a critical piece of infrastructure.</description></item><item><title>setting up tidal cycles</title><link>https://theleo.zone/posts/tidal-cycles-setup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/posts/tidal-cycles-setup/</guid><description>Tidal Cycles is software that works on top of another piece of software called SuperCollider.
Together, you can use them to produce music using code.
Today I set up these tools and made my first sound with them. Setup was a bit tricky, and this post is as much for myself to document what I did as it is for others pursuing their own setup in the future.
The first step is to install SuperCollider, following the install links for your platform at supercollider.</description></item><item><title>cron: for your health</title><link>https://theleo.zone/posts/cron-for-your-health/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/posts/cron-for-your-health/</guid><description>I have a standing desk, but rarely stand. I have probably been sitting about 7 hours a day, which is too much! In the spirit of positive nudges for habit building and taking ownership over my notifications, I wrote a simple cron job to remind me to stand up every hour.
Note that this is mac-specific, but a Linux or Windows analog should be fairly easy to implement.
~/projects/cron/standup.sh
#!/usr/bin/env sh osascript -e &amp;#39;display alert &amp;#34;Stand up and stretch!</description></item><item><title>local typescript sandbox</title><link>https://theleo.zone/posts/typescript-sandbox/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 17:16:07 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/posts/typescript-sandbox/</guid><description>I made a simple live-reloading Typescript sandbox, similar to the Vanilla Typescript CodeSandbox but running locally.
You can run it with node installed or in a docker container.
I like having a Typescript-ready environment without having to spinup a new react app or something. CodeSandbox was nice, but got pretty laggy at times and was hard to version control. Gluing together some tooling to scratch my own itch was fun.</description></item><item><title>rodney mullen and mastery</title><link>https://theleo.zone/posts/rodney-mullen-and-mastery/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2021 14:11:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/posts/rodney-mullen-and-mastery/</guid><description>Today, I fell asleep on the couch watching youtube and woke up halfway through a Rodney Mullen documentary.
Rodney Mullen, like Simone Biles in gymnastics or Derren Brown in magic, is one of the best that will ever be in their domain. World champ at 14, inventor of the ollie and kickflip, a laundry list of other accolades&amp;hellip;there&amp;rsquo;s not much to dispute.
The podium finishers at the olympics this year in Skateboarding, while insanely skilled, won their medals doing stuff that doesn&amp;rsquo;t look much different than what Mullen was doing in the 80&amp;rsquo;s.</description></item><item><title>verbify your arrows</title><link>https://theleo.zone/posts/verbify-your-arrows/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 22:36:07 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/posts/verbify-your-arrows/</guid><description>This is a diagram from an open source project I was evaluating at work recently, and the subsequent conversations I had:
Me: So their solution is push based?
Coworker: No, I think they just specify the general protocol.
Me: But those lines from the squares at the top to the central circle sort of look like arrows, don&amp;rsquo;t they? And their client pushes data&amp;hellip;I think maybe it&amp;rsquo;s push based?
Coworker: Yea, it&amp;rsquo;s unclear&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>react html5 zoom/pan canvas</title><link>https://theleo.zone/posts/html-canvas-pan-zoom-react/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 21:47:48 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/posts/html-canvas-pan-zoom-react/</guid><description>A pannable, mouse-centered zoomable, HTML5 canvas template in React + Typescript. You&amp;rsquo;d think this would be a solved problem, but despite the plethora of solutions out there, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t get quite what I wanted for some time. Finally, here it all is in one place for future me and others to use as boilerplate for their embedded interactive canvases in their apps.
If you see any bugs or possible improvements, please comment on the gist here:</description></item><item><title>code and plant advents</title><link>https://theleo.zone/posts/code-and-plant-advents/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/posts/code-and-plant-advents/</guid><description>Last month, I participated in advent of code for the first time. Everyday from Dec 1st through 25th, a problem is released. Each problem requires some programming to solve, and is split into two separate but related parts.
The problem statements link to an overarching narrative involving a character going on vacation and encountering a number of technical difficulties, e.g. implementing a ticket reader for the train or a fixing the boot code in your neighbours airplane video game console.</description></item><item><title>giving what we can pledge</title><link>https://theleo.zone/posts/the-giving-pledge/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 16:48:23 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/posts/the-giving-pledge/</guid><description>This is a bit of an uncomfortable public post for me. Talking about money in general can be uncomfortable, and talking about giving money can just come off as self-congratulatory. But I think it&amp;rsquo;s an important topic that will have positive impact when talked about more often.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been excited about GiveWell for a while now, and am interested in exploring the idea of doing the most good with money, time and effort.</description></item><item><title>css shapes</title><link>https://theleo.zone/posts/css-shapes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 14:03:25 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/posts/css-shapes/</guid><description> Today I spent some time learning more about how to draw with css. You can make a lot of shapes and designs with only css! I went off of https://css-tricks.com/the-shapes-of-css/.
nomnom</description></item><item><title>color commentary</title><link>https://theleo.zone/posts/color-commentary/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 09:42:53 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/posts/color-commentary/</guid><description>Twitter bird - blue or purple? About 6 weeks ago, I launched colorcontroversy.com. Since then, the site has collected over 800,000 color judgements and been shared around the web more than I expected.
A much-simplified version of Randal Monroe of XKCD&amp;rsquo;s color survey, the site shows you a color shade and presents two color choices for that shade. For example, it shows you a dark turquoise and asks you if it&amp;rsquo;s Green or Blue.</description></item><item><title>covid projects</title><link>https://theleo.zone/posts/covid-projects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/posts/covid-projects/</guid><description>I have been very fortunate to remain employed during this global pandemic. My productivity working from home has been about on par with what I had in the office, although my learning rate has gone down a bit due to the lack of water-cooler style chats about the product and software in general. We use Slack for remote chat and it feels a bit too formal to trigger notifications for offhand questions.</description></item><item><title>gifting websites</title><link>https://theleo.zone/posts/gifting-websites/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/posts/gifting-websites/</guid><description>Over the past year or so, I have gifted friends a few websites. I think the sites are fun, relatively unique gifts. As a bonus serve, they illustrate some of my progression with basic html/css/javascript static websites.
Site 1: averyrobins.com I set up an Amazon S3 bucket for static hosting, bought a namecheap domain name, configured the custom DNS, and voila - I now pay $1/month to host this profanity-laden ASCII art.</description></item><item><title>RC 11 (fin)</title><link>https://theleo.zone/recurse/rc-11-fin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/recurse/rc-11-fin/</guid><description>In the last few days, I&amp;rsquo;ve gone from RC in Brooklyn to moving back to San Francisco to currently sitting on a plane to the Dominican Republic.
Recurse is over! It happened! What an excellent time.
I got a lot out of projects, reading, meet ups, interviewing and online courses. The study and research was varied and rewarding.
In the end, though, I got as much or more from being around the people at RC as the individual study.</description></item><item><title>RC 10 (work)</title><link>https://theleo.zone/recurse/rc-10-work/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/recurse/rc-10-work/</guid><description>&amp;#39;Chad, destroyer of worlds&amp;#39; - circa 2015 My second to last week at RC was first spent in San Francisco at onsite interviews for positions in the city. Interviews went well and I had a nice time seeing some friends while there.
Unfortunately, there wasn&amp;rsquo;t enough time to finish the compiler of nand2tetris! The first week where I haven&amp;rsquo;t finished my nand2tetris project :&amp;rsquo;(. I&amp;rsquo;m going to try my best to finish up both the compiler and OS this final week, though!</description></item><item><title>RC 09 (λεξικόν)</title><link>https://theleo.zone/recurse/rc-09-%CE%BB%CE%B5%CE%BE%CE%B9%CE%BA%CF%8C%CE%BD/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/recurse/rc-09-%CE%BB%CE%B5%CE%BE%CE%B9%CE%BA%CF%8C%CE%BD/</guid><description>In my third to last week of RC (!!!), I learned about Nix, Jest for Test Driven Development in Javascript, completed project 10 of nand2tetris, and continued interview prep.
Project 10 consists of the first half of the Jack compiler. The overall compiler is split in to tokenization + lexical analysis (project 10) and VM code generation (project 11).
The first half of the compiler was the most time consuming project of the course so far.</description></item><item><title>RC 08 (mooninites)</title><link>https://theleo.zone/recurse/rc-08-mooninites/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/recurse/rc-08-mooninites/</guid><description>Aqua Teen Hunger Force&amp;#39;s Mooninites This week, I completed Nand2Tetris project 9, wrote about Givewell, and continued interview prep.
Nand2Tetris&amp;rsquo; gets you used to programming in the high-level &amp;ldquo;Jack&amp;rdquo; programming language. It would be difficult (or at least, less meaningful) to write a compiler for a high level language that you don&amp;rsquo;t really understand.
I found it useful in that it solidified the rules of Jack and allowed me to project my thoughts of what the compiler would be doing to translate Jack code to VM Code.</description></item><item><title>givewell is awesome</title><link>https://theleo.zone/posts/givewell-is-awesome/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/posts/givewell-is-awesome/</guid><description>Note: this is my personal commentary and this post is not officially endorsed by Givewell in any way.
Givewell is one of the most admirable philanthropic organizations out there. They recognize and act upon a number of important truths:
Money is a super powerful tool for reducing harm in the world Money can be used in more and less effective ways The effectiveness of money can be modeled with finite (possibly wide) uncertainty bounds at a non-trivial confidence level Encouraging those with the means to donate money to effective causes is important and worthwhile Moral judgement is an inseparable part of judging the effectiveness of an outcome Not only does Givewell maintain an active blog, a Giving 101 section of its site, run free events in the Bay Area every few months and deliver well-curated email updates, but they keep updated copies of their Cost Effectiveness Models and Guide to Cost Effective Analysis available online for everyone to view.</description></item><item><title>RC 07 (fib 5 ways)</title><link>https://theleo.zone/recurse/rc-07-fib-5-ways/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/recurse/rc-07-fib-5-ways/</guid><description>Recurse continues!
Each successive number in the Fibonacci Sequence is the sum of the two prior numbers:
0, 1, 1, 2, 3, 5, 8, 13...
While learning about algorithms and doing nand2tetris, I&amp;rsquo;ve come across the Fibonacci Sequence a number of times. Here are a 5 ways to calculate the Nth element of the sequence:
Method 1: Recursion Recursion is when a function calls itself. Intuitively, it&amp;rsquo;s a top down approach to problem solving.</description></item><item><title>RC 06 (intermediate representations)</title><link>https://theleo.zone/recurse/rc-06-intermediate-representations/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/recurse/rc-06-intermediate-representations/</guid><description>I wrapped up Nand2Tetris project 6 and completed project 7 this week. One satisfying thing about this course has been consistently connecting the &amp;ldquo;simple&amp;rdquo; implementations that the course outlines to the hyper complex implementations in the real world.
Project 7 outlined the idea of multi-stage compilation. Take a high level language and compile it to a &amp;ldquo;Virtual Machine Code&amp;rdquo;, with readable but lower level syntax. This &amp;ldquo;intermediate representation&amp;rdquo; can then be compiled further through assembly to machine code (the 1s and 0s) for a specific hardware platform (e.</description></item><item><title>RC 05 (your biggest weakness)</title><link>https://theleo.zone/recurse/rc-05-your-biggest-weakness/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/recurse/rc-05-your-biggest-weakness/</guid><description>80,000 Hours is a non-profit that researches the world&amp;rsquo;s most pressing problems and provides guidance on how to make an impact on them with your career. Apart from the whole &amp;ldquo;saving the world&amp;rdquo; focus, what I love about their basic premise is that your career matters.
Not only does it matter to you, who will be the one living it out every day and week and month for approximately 80,000 hours, but it matters to the world what you do.</description></item><item><title>concurrency in python</title><link>https://theleo.zone/posts/concurrency-in-python/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/posts/concurrency-in-python/</guid><description>Concurrency ! easy is Concurrency is of paramount importance in modern computing. It is a complex domain in itself, with major contributions from database development, machine learning, distributed application deployment, and academia.
Python requires a clear and simple concurrency framework as it is commonly used in high-compute settings like training neural networks. Matrix algebra has been made fast with NumPy and related tools, interfacing with C to get large performance improvements.</description></item><item><title>RC 04 (all the wrong type)</title><link>https://theleo.zone/recurse/rc-04-all-the-wrong-type/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/recurse/rc-04-all-the-wrong-type/</guid><description>This week, the hack computer&amp;rsquo;s hardware was completed with project 5 of Nand2Tetris! I decided to write the remaining software portion of the course (projects 6-12) in Rust, feeding two birds with one scone.
The Mandelbrot set with Rust Source: http://downloads.codecoding.com/rust/Programming%20Rust.pdf While I started learning Rust with the the O&amp;rsquo;Reilly Book, I&amp;rsquo;ve found The Rust Programming Language and Rustlings to be great resources as well. It was also incredibly helpful when Evan installed Rust Language Server (RLS) in my VSCode environment, making it easy to view source code and highlighting errors before compile time.</description></item><item><title>statistical bias</title><link>https://theleo.zone/posts/statistical-bias/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/posts/statistical-bias/</guid><description>Eat my spheres! You find yourself trapped in a room with Jigsaw, the villain from the Saw movies. There is a wood box of 100 spheres, some of them steel ball bearings and some of them gumballs. Jigsaw tells you that you can leave the room alive if you guess the number of steel ball bearings in the jar correctly. You can pull 10 random spheres out the 100 in the box as many times as you want, but each time you do, you have to eat all of them (yum!</description></item><item><title>linear regression</title><link>https://theleo.zone/posts/linear-regression/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/posts/linear-regression/</guid><description>Update 2019-10-25: Added MLE derivation and OLS $ \sigma^2 $
I have learned linear regression a number of times with varying of levels of detail. I&amp;rsquo;m making this document mostly as a reference for myself and any others who may be interested in the technique.
The concepts and explanations here come either from An Introduction to Statistical Learning (ISLR) or The Elements of Statistical Learning (ESLR). Other sources are listed at the bottom.</description></item><item><title>RC 03 (regressing linearly)</title><link>https://theleo.zone/recurse/rc-03-regressing-linearly/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/recurse/rc-03-regressing-linearly/</guid><description>This week, I completed project 4 of Nand2Tetris, updated my resume and converted it to a responsive web page, and learned a whole lot about linear regression.
Nand2Tetris project 4 breaks away from the Hardware Description Language of the first three projects and moves in to a pseudo assembly code. This assembly language is specifically written for the &amp;ldquo;Hack&amp;rdquo; computer that the class builds up through the first six projects. Writing in &amp;ldquo;assembly&amp;rdquo; is one step down from writing in something like C - there is no automatic memory management, only a couple registers to play with, lots of referencing addresses with pointers and semi-roundabout ways of doing things.</description></item><item><title>RC 02 (R, wavey!)</title><link>https://theleo.zone/recurse/rc-02-r-wavey/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/recurse/rc-02-r-wavey/</guid><description>This week, I completed project 3 of Nand2Tetris, learned some deeper fundamentals of statistical learning in R, and wrote my first interactive thing in D3.
D3.js is a widely used javascript library for creating beautiful, interactive visualizations on the web. I made quite a simple interactive sine wave plotter, but the exercise took hours and really helped me gain insight in to D3&amp;rsquo;s declarative approach to data-centric object manipulation. Code for the thing here.</description></item><item><title>RC 01 (logic immunity)</title><link>https://theleo.zone/recurse/rc-01-logic-immunity/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/recurse/rc-01-logic-immunity/</guid><description>I have been learning about basic computer architecture (logic gates) and working on a herd immunity simulation.
Computer architecture work has come from the awesome Nand2Tetris course by Shimon Schocken and Noam Nisan. Shimon has a fantastic Ted Talk about the course and many Recursers have done it in the past. I&amp;rsquo;m 2 projects in to the first half of the course (Coursera link)
The premise is that you start with a Nand (&amp;ldquo;Not And&amp;rdquo;) logic gate.</description></item><item><title>jupyter with docker</title><link>https://theleo.zone/posts/jupyter-with-docker/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/posts/jupyter-with-docker/</guid><description>I love docker. It makes environments:
portable across any machine subject to version control (retraceable and recoverable history) easily deployed and discarded with simple commands Jupyter is a great tool that allows for the creation of nice looking documents consisting of ordered code chunks with inline output. It is a fantastic way to get started with programming, clearly step through your workflow, and/or create stories and presentations out of your work.</description></item><item><title>RC 00 (it begins)</title><link>https://theleo.zone/recurse/rc-00-it-begins/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/recurse/rc-00-it-begins/</guid><description>It is day 3 at the Recurse Center (RC)!
Me experimenting with Haskell and Rust It has been a whirlwind of orientation, meeting awesome people, learning about (and about the existence of) new cool things, setting up and settling in.
This was my second day here:
8-9am: Research blogging tools to create this very website. Decide on Jekyll + github pages + namecheap domain as a good solution 9-10am: Update MacOS to Mojave after experiencing ruby-related jekyll issues 10-11am: Using this great tutorial, get jekyll and bundler installed.</description></item><item><title>about me</title><link>https://theleo.zone/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/about/</guid><description>A small collection of real and questionably real endorsements:
We just watched your presentation on Wander on YouTube. We are both proud and baffled. Proud of your work and your fluent ability to speak a new English. Baffled because we feel a bit like having been dropped into a Helsinki lecture theatre listening to an eloquent prof speaking in faultless Finnish. Like your comments it would be lovely to the ears and practically meaningless to the mind.</description></item><item><title>Hansel &amp; Gretel's Internet Lounge</title><link>https://theleo.zone/hansel-and-gretel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/hansel-and-gretel/</guid><description>🎉 UPDATE 🎉
Hansel &amp;amp; Gretel have been adopted into a loving home!!!
You really couldn&amp;rsquo;t ask for better cats.
Gretel is the shorter haired tortoiseshell cat. She is an explorative cuddler who will paw at your arm gently if you stop petting her too early.
Hansel is a sprawl-in-your-lap kinda guy. A black furry boy, he sheds surprisingly little and is sleek, clean, and has beautiful orange eyes.</description></item><item><title>Jerald Chaim "Jerry" Robinovitch</title><link>https://theleo.zone/jerry/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/jerry/</guid><description>Stories and images from Jerry&amp;rsquo;s ninth life, lived from April 23, 2021 to May 28, 2022 I wanted a cat. My new apartment allowed them, and they are pretty neat. A friend recommended Jerry, a 15 year old orange boy from the SPCA. I had already applied for him.
Prior Jerry adoption applicants had been deterred by his various medical conditions. Stage one kidney failure, heart murmur, just had some teeth pulled and benign lumps removed&amp;hellip;sounds like a hassle.</description></item><item><title>Phoenix's Tumblr Page</title><link>https://theleo.zone/phoenix/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/phoenix/</guid><description>🎉 UPDATE 🎉
Phoenix has been adopted into a loving home!!!
Phoenix is an old girl who has come here to cuddle you and eat food. And she&amp;rsquo;s all out of food.
She is incredibly sweet, with a deep love for head bumps and neck scritches. She sleeps on my bed at my feet and doesn&amp;rsquo;t disturb my slumber. She&amp;rsquo;s a bit overweight and does a funny little booty wiggle before hopping up on the couch or bed.</description></item></channel></rss>