<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Books on Leo Robinovitch @ The Leo Zone</title><link>https://theleo.zone/books/</link><description>Recent content in Books on Leo Robinovitch @ The Leo Zone</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://theleo.zone/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Book Review: The Shadow of What Was Lost</title><link>https://theleo.zone/books/the-shadow-of-what-was-lost/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/books/the-shadow-of-what-was-lost/</guid><description>Rating: 🪄
The Shadow of What Was Lost is the first book in The Licanius Trilogy, a fantasy series by James Islington.
I really enjoyed this book. As usual, spoilers ahead.
The setting in this book feels huge. It&amp;rsquo;s like a Marvel Movie in High fantasy format, seriously, it&amp;rsquo;s a super hero book more than a fantasy book. In Brandon Sanderson&amp;rsquo;s worlds, he introduces a structured magical mechanic that influences physics or physical abilities, like the Allomantic metals in Mistborn or the Stormlight in The Stormlight Archive.</description></item><item><title>Book Review: The Diamond Age</title><link>https://theleo.zone/books/the-diamond-age/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/books/the-diamond-age/</guid><description>Rating: 👎
Heavily opinionated claims and spoilers ahead.
I did not enjoy and do not recommend The Diamond Age, by Neil Stephenson. It was a particularly disappointing read for me because of how much I enjoyed Snow Crash last month.
The Diamond Age should be called The Rough (Unpolished) Diamond, as this could have been a great book. Imagining what a post-scarcity world full of accessible nanotechnology and universal 3D &amp;ldquo;matter printers&amp;rdquo; looks like is cool!</description></item><item><title>Book Review: Snow Crash</title><link>https://theleo.zone/books/snow-crash/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/books/snow-crash/</guid><description>Rating: ❄️📉
My experiences took on a different texture while I read Snow Crash by Neal Stephenson. The hyper-privatized, segmented-but-uniform world in which the plot unfolds gave me greater than usual mistrust for every McDonalds, gated community, and Airport shopping corridor.
As usual, spoilers ahead.
I loved the characters in Snow Crash. A mutant Aleut killer who uses glass knives and has a Hydrogen bomb synced to go off if he&amp;rsquo;s killed.</description></item><item><title>Book Review: The Scholomance Series</title><link>https://theleo.zone/books/the-scholomance-series/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/books/the-scholomance-series/</guid><description>Rating: 🧙‍♀️
If you enjoyed Harry Potter, The Magicians by Lev Grossman, or Game of Thrones, then you will probably have a great time with The Scholomance Series by Naomi Novik.
Warning: spoilers ahead.
The trilogy starts with the pedal to the metal. Soul sucking monsters, heroism, and drama in a boarding school for magical teens.
At first it felt like I was reading the journal of an overly melodramatic teenage girl, El.</description></item><item><title>Book Review: The Art of Learning</title><link>https://theleo.zone/books/the-art-of-learning/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/books/the-art-of-learning/</guid><description>Rating: 📈
A self help book usually acts like a manual for achieving above-average levels of success, wealth, positive mental state, etc., told through parables of the author&amp;rsquo;s life.
What qualities do we find distasteful in self help books?
taking it as a given that everyone should uncritically strive to dominate and win within a conventional framework of success claims that you, yes you, can dominate, win, and succeed like the author if you just follow these steps encouraging exploitation of others in order to win pushing pseudoscience, a la &amp;ldquo;Scientists hate this one simple trick&amp;rdquo; (positive thinking, law of attraction, etc.</description></item><item><title>Book Review: The Code Book</title><link>https://theleo.zone/books/the-code-book/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/books/the-code-book/</guid><description>Rating: 🧨
I picked up The Code Book at a used book store in Seattle, honestly expecting it to be a nonstarter. Another book on an interesting technical topic that assumes the reader has a PhD in the field or that they&amp;rsquo;d shrivel up at the first whiff of math.
I am happy to report that I was wrong! This is the best book I&amp;rsquo;ve read in the last year.</description></item></channel></rss>