<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Books on Leo Robinovitch @ The Leo Zone</title><link>https://theleo.zone/books/</link><description>Recent content in Books on Leo Robinovitch @ The Leo Zone</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://theleo.zone/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Book Review: The Scholomance Series</title><link>https://theleo.zone/books/the-scholomance-series/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/books/the-scholomance-series/</guid><description>Rating: 🧙‍♀️
If you enjoyed Harry Potter, The Magicians by Lev Grossman, or Game of Thrones, then you will probably have a great time with The Scholomance Series by Naomi Novik.
Warning: spoilers ahead.
The trilogy starts with the pedal to the metal. Soul sucking monsters, heroism, and drama in a boarding school for magical teens.
At first it felt like I was reading the journal of an overly melodramatic teenage girl, El.</description></item><item><title>Book Review: The Art of Learning</title><link>https://theleo.zone/books/the-art-of-learning/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/books/the-art-of-learning/</guid><description>Rating: 📈
A self help book usually acts like a manual for achieving above-average levels of success, wealth, positive mental state, etc., told through parables of the author&amp;rsquo;s life.
What qualities do we find distasteful in self help books?
taking it as a given that everyone should uncritically strive to dominate and win within a conventional framework of success claims that you, yes you, can dominate, win, and succeed like the author if you just follow these steps encouraging exploitation of others in order to win pushing pseudoscience, a la &amp;ldquo;Scientists hate this one simple trick&amp;rdquo; (positive thinking, law of attraction, etc.</description></item><item><title>Book Review: The Code Book</title><link>https://theleo.zone/books/the-code-book/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/books/the-code-book/</guid><description>Rating: 🧨
I picked up The Code Book at a used book store in Seattle, honestly expecting it to be a nonstarter. Another book on an interesting technical topic that assumes the reader has a PhD in the field or that they&amp;rsquo;d shrivel up at the first whiff of math.
I am happy to report that I was wrong! This is the best book I&amp;rsquo;ve read in the last year.</description></item></channel></rss>