<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Books on Leo Robinovitch @ The Leo Zone</title><link>https://theleo.zone/books/</link><description>Recent content in Books on Leo Robinovitch @ The Leo Zone</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://theleo.zone/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Book Review: The Devil in the White City</title><link>https://theleo.zone/books/the-devil-in-the-white-city/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/books/the-devil-in-the-white-city/</guid><description>Rating: 👹
The Devil in the White City is a book by Erik Larson about the 1893 World&amp;rsquo;s Columbian Exposition (&amp;ldquo;the fair&amp;rdquo;) in Chicago. It follows two main characters: Daniel Burnham, the fair&amp;rsquo;s primary architect, and H. H. Holmes, a serial killer who operated during the time of the fair.
I&amp;rsquo;m a bit late to the party on this one. It was big after it came out in 2003, and my mom recommended it to me at least 5 years ago, but 2023 seems like my year of Chicago - watching The Bear, putting together that something like 20% of my friends are from Chicago, and now this book.</description></item><item><title>Book Review: Unreasonable Hospitality</title><link>https://theleo.zone/books/unreasonable-hospitality/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/books/unreasonable-hospitality/</guid><description>Rating: 🧑‍🍳💋
Unreasonable Hospitality is a book by Will Guidara about his experience in the restaurant industry. In particular, he writes about managing Eleven Madison Park (EMP) for 11 years, taking it from a &amp;ldquo;mere&amp;rdquo; 2 stars to being awarded the prize of best restaurant in the world.
Guidara is the first to call out the silliness and practical importance of this award:
&amp;hellip;it’s absolutely ridiculous to call any restaurant “the best restaurant in the world.</description></item><item><title>Book Review: Designing Data Intensive Applications</title><link>https://theleo.zone/books/designing-data-intensive-applications/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/books/designing-data-intensive-applications/</guid><description>Rating: 📀
Designing Data Intensive Applications (DDIA) is a book by Martin Kleppmann.
How do I review this incredible reference? I&amp;rsquo;ll first say that if you program professionally, you should read this book. It will introduce you to new ideas and help you clarify and reconceptualize ones you may already be familiar with. You are very likely to find relevance to your work in multiple chapters. You can view my abridged notes in Notion here if you&amp;rsquo;d like.</description></item><item><title>Book Review: Tomorrow, and Tomorrow, and Tomorrow</title><link>https://theleo.zone/books/tomorrow-and-tomorrow-and-tomorrow/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/books/tomorrow-and-tomorrow-and-tomorrow/</guid><description>Rating:👾
Tomorrow, and Tomorrow, and Tomorrow (T3) is a novel by Gabrielle Zevin.
I really enjoyed this book, ripping through it on my flight and subsequent jetlagged morning as I move back from London to the West Coast. Spoilers ahead.
Many people I know have read and enjoyed this book in the past months. Zevin mentions some influences in her author&amp;rsquo;s note at the end, and summarizes that the book is about Work and it is about Love, and that struck me as a good summary.</description></item><item><title>Book Review: The Light of All That Falls</title><link>https://theleo.zone/books/the-light-of-all-that-falls/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/books/the-light-of-all-that-falls/</guid><description>Rating:🔦
The Light of All That Falls is the third and final book in The Licanius Trilogy, a fantasy series by James Islington.
The book nicely rounds out this excellent series. Spoilers ahead.
This series really emphasizes that everyone thinks that they are doing what is best for the world. Aarkein Devaed and the Venerate believed that releasing &amp;ldquo;El&amp;rdquo; is the way to grant people freedom of choice and undo the harms of the past.</description></item><item><title>Book Review: An Echo of Things to Come</title><link>https://theleo.zone/books/an-echo-of-things-to-come/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/books/an-echo-of-things-to-come/</guid><description>Rating:🗼
An Echo of Things to Come is the second book in The Licanius Trilogy, a fantasy series by James Islington.
I enjoyed the second book here even more than the first. As usual, spoilers ahead.
The first book left a large volume of unexplained content, and at first, it seemed like that was just going to grow throughout the second book. I was worried, becausing explaining all of it in the trilogy&amp;rsquo;s finale would be pretty ambitious.</description></item><item><title>Book Review: The Shadow of What Was Lost</title><link>https://theleo.zone/books/the-shadow-of-what-was-lost/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/books/the-shadow-of-what-was-lost/</guid><description>Rating: 🪄
The Shadow of What Was Lost is the first book in The Licanius Trilogy, a fantasy series by James Islington.
I really enjoyed this book. As usual, spoilers ahead.
The setting in this book feels huge. It&amp;rsquo;s like a Marvel Movie in High fantasy format, seriously, it&amp;rsquo;s a super hero book more than a fantasy book. In Brandon Sanderson&amp;rsquo;s worlds, he introduces a structured magical mechanic that influences physics or physical abilities, like the Allomantic metals in Mistborn or the Stormlight in The Stormlight Archive.</description></item><item><title>Book Review: The Diamond Age</title><link>https://theleo.zone/books/the-diamond-age/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/books/the-diamond-age/</guid><description>Rating: 👎
Heavily opinionated claims and spoilers ahead.
I did not enjoy and do not recommend The Diamond Age, by Neil Stephenson. It was a particularly disappointing read for me because of how much I enjoyed Snow Crash last month.
The Diamond Age should be called The Rough (Unpolished) Diamond, as this could have been a great book. Imagining what a post-scarcity world full of accessible nanotechnology and universal 3D &amp;ldquo;matter printers&amp;rdquo; looks like is cool!</description></item><item><title>Book Review: Snow Crash</title><link>https://theleo.zone/books/snow-crash/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/books/snow-crash/</guid><description>Rating: ❄️📉
My experiences took on a different texture while I read Snow Crash by Neal Stephenson. The hyper-privatized, segmented-but-uniform world in which the plot unfolds gave me greater than usual mistrust for every McDonalds, gated community, and Airport shopping corridor.
As usual, spoilers ahead.
I loved the characters in Snow Crash. A mutant Aleut killer who uses glass knives and has a Hydrogen bomb synced to go off if he&amp;rsquo;s killed.</description></item><item><title>Book Review: The Scholomance Series</title><link>https://theleo.zone/books/the-scholomance-series/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/books/the-scholomance-series/</guid><description>Rating: 🧙‍♀️
If you enjoyed Harry Potter, The Magicians by Lev Grossman, or Game of Thrones, then you will probably have a great time with The Scholomance Series by Naomi Novik.
Warning: spoilers ahead.
The trilogy starts with the pedal to the metal. Soul sucking monsters, heroism, and drama in a boarding school for magical teens.
At first it felt like I was reading the journal of an overly melodramatic teenage girl, El.</description></item><item><title>Book Review: The Art of Learning</title><link>https://theleo.zone/books/the-art-of-learning/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/books/the-art-of-learning/</guid><description>Rating: 📈
A self help book usually acts like a manual for achieving above-average levels of success, wealth, positive mental state, etc., told through parables of the author&amp;rsquo;s life.
What qualities do we find distasteful in self help books?
taking it as a given that everyone should uncritically strive to dominate and win within a conventional framework of success claims that you, yes you, can dominate, win, and succeed like the author if you just follow these steps encouraging exploitation of others in order to win pushing pseudoscience, a la &amp;ldquo;Scientists hate this one simple trick&amp;rdquo; (positive thinking, law of attraction, etc.</description></item><item><title>Book Review: The Code Book</title><link>https://theleo.zone/books/the-code-book/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/books/the-code-book/</guid><description>Rating: 🧨
I picked up The Code Book at a used book store in Seattle, honestly expecting it to be a nonstarter. Another book on an interesting technical topic that assumes the reader has a PhD in the field or that they&amp;rsquo;d shrivel up at the first whiff of math.
I am happy to report that I was wrong! This is the best book I&amp;rsquo;ve read in the last year.</description></item></channel></rss>