<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on The Leo Zone</title><link>https://theleo.zone/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on The Leo Zone</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://theleo.zone/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>migrating kafka to amazon msk</title><link>https://theleo.zone/posts/migrating-to-msk/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/posts/migrating-to-msk/</guid><description>I work on the software team at Voltus. We orchestrate distributed energy resources-large-scale electricity users, residential consumers, batteries, and generators-to make the electric grid more resilient and pay our customers well.
This is the story of migrating one hundred microservices from self-managed Kafka in Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (Amazon EC2) to Amazon Managed Streaming for Apache Kafka (Amazon MSK).
Initial State Kafka was introduced to the Voltus tech stack in 2019 and quickly became a critical piece of infrastructure.</description></item><item><title>setting up tidal cycles</title><link>https://theleo.zone/posts/tidal-cycles-setup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/posts/tidal-cycles-setup/</guid><description>Tidal Cycles is software that works on top of another piece of software called SuperCollider.
Together, you can use them to produce music using code.
Today I set up these tools and made my first sound with them. Setup was a bit tricky, and this post is as much for myself to document what I did as it is for others pursuing their own setup in the future.
The first step is to install SuperCollider, following the install links for your platform at supercollider.</description></item><item><title>cron: for your health</title><link>https://theleo.zone/posts/cron-for-your-health/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/posts/cron-for-your-health/</guid><description>I have a standing desk, but rarely stand. I have probably been sitting about 7 hours a day, which is too much! In the spirit of positive nudges for habit building and taking ownership over my notifications, I wrote a simple cron job to remind me to stand up every hour.
Note that this is mac-specific, but a Linux or Windows analog should be fairly easy to implement.
~/projects/cron/standup.sh
1 2 3 #!</description></item><item><title>local typescript sandbox</title><link>https://theleo.zone/posts/typescript-sandbox/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 17:16:07 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/posts/typescript-sandbox/</guid><description>I made a simple live-reloading Typescript sandbox, similar to the Vanilla Typescript CodeSandbox but running locally.
You can run it with node installed or in a docker container.
I like having a Typescript-ready environment without having to spinup a new react app or something. CodeSandbox was nice, but got pretty laggy at times and was hard to version control. Gluing together some tooling to scratch my own itch was fun.</description></item><item><title>rodney mullen and mastery</title><link>https://theleo.zone/posts/rodney-mullen-and-mastery/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2021 14:11:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/posts/rodney-mullen-and-mastery/</guid><description>Today, I fell asleep on the couch watching youtube and woke up halfway through a Rodney Mullen documentary.
Rodney Mullen, like Simone Biles in gymnastics or Derren Brown in magic, is one of the best that will ever be in their domain. World champ at 14, inventor of the ollie and kickflip, a laundry list of other accolades&amp;hellip;there&amp;rsquo;s not much to dispute.
The podium finishers at the olympics this year in Skateboarding, while insanely skilled, won their medals doing stuff that doesn&amp;rsquo;t look much different than what Mullen was doing in the 80&amp;rsquo;s.</description></item><item><title>verbify your arrows</title><link>https://theleo.zone/posts/verbify-your-arrows/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 22:36:07 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/posts/verbify-your-arrows/</guid><description>This is a diagram from an open source project I was evaluating at work recently, and the subsequent conversations I had:
Me: So their solution is push based?
Coworker: No, I think they just specify the general protocol.
Me: But those lines from the squares at the top to the central circle sort of look like arrows, don&amp;rsquo;t they? And their client pushes data&amp;hellip;I think maybe it&amp;rsquo;s push based?
Coworker: Yea, it&amp;rsquo;s unclear&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>react html5 zoom/pan canvas</title><link>https://theleo.zone/posts/html-canvas-pan-zoom-react/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 21:47:48 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/posts/html-canvas-pan-zoom-react/</guid><description>A pannable, mouse-centered zoomable, HTML5 canvas template in React + Typescript. You&amp;rsquo;d think this would be a solved problem, but despite the plethora of solutions out there, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t get quite what I wanted for some time. Finally, here it all is in one place for future me and others to use as boilerplate for their embedded interactive canvases in their apps.
If you see any bugs or possible improvements, please comment on the gist here:</description></item><item><title>code and plant advents</title><link>https://theleo.zone/posts/code-and-plant-advents/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/posts/code-and-plant-advents/</guid><description>Last month, I participated in advent of code for the first time. Everyday from Dec 1st through 25th, a problem is released. Each problem requires some programming to solve, and is split into two separate but related parts.
The problem statements link to an overarching narrative involving a character going on vacation and encountering a number of technical difficulties, e.g. implementing a ticket reader for the train or a fixing the boot code in your neighbours airplane video game console.</description></item><item><title>giving what we can pledge</title><link>https://theleo.zone/posts/the-giving-pledge/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 16:48:23 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/posts/the-giving-pledge/</guid><description>This is a bit of an uncomfortable public post for me. Talking about money in general can be uncomfortable, and talking about giving money can just come off as self-congratulatory. But I think it&amp;rsquo;s an important topic that will have positive impact when talked about more often.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been excited about GiveWell for a while now, and am interested in exploring the idea of doing the most good with money, time and effort.</description></item><item><title>css shapes</title><link>https://theleo.zone/posts/css-shapes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 14:03:25 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/posts/css-shapes/</guid><description> Today I spent some time learning more about how to draw with css. You can make a lot of shapes and designs with only css! I went off of https://css-tricks.com/the-shapes-of-css/.
nomnom</description></item><item><title>color commentary</title><link>https://theleo.zone/posts/color-commentary/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 09:42:53 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/posts/color-commentary/</guid><description>Twitter bird - blue or purple? About 6 weeks ago, I launched colorcontroversy.com. Since then, the site has collected over 800,000 color judgements and been shared around the web more than I expected.
A much-simplified version of Randal Monroe of XKCD&amp;rsquo;s color survey, the site shows you a color shade and presents two color choices for that shade. For example, it shows you a dark turquoise and asks you if it&amp;rsquo;s Green or Blue.</description></item><item><title>covid projects</title><link>https://theleo.zone/posts/covid-projects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/posts/covid-projects/</guid><description>I have been very fortunate to remain employed during this global pandemic. My productivity working from home has been about on par with what I had in the office, although my learning rate has gone down a bit due to the lack of water-cooler style chats about the product and software in general. We use Slack for remote chat and it feels a bit too formal to trigger notifications for offhand questions.</description></item><item><title>gifting websites</title><link>https://theleo.zone/posts/gifting-websites/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/posts/gifting-websites/</guid><description>Over the past year or so, I have gifted friends a few websites. I think the sites are fun, relatively unique gifts. As a bonus serve, they illustrate some of my progression with basic html/css/javascript static websites.
Site 1: averyrobins.com I set up an Amazon S3 bucket for static hosting, bought a namecheap domain name, configured the custom DNS, and voila - I now pay $1/month to host this profanity-laden ASCII art.</description></item><item><title>givewell is awesome</title><link>https://theleo.zone/posts/givewell-is-awesome/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/posts/givewell-is-awesome/</guid><description>Note: this is my personal commentary and this post is not officially endorsed by Givewell in any way.
Givewell is one of the most admirable philanthropic organizations out there. They recognize and act upon a number of important truths:
Money is a super powerful tool for reducing harm in the world Money can be used in more and less effective ways The effectiveness of money can be modeled with finite (possibly wide) uncertainty bounds at a non-trivial confidence level Encouraging those with the means to donate money to effective causes is important and worthwhile Moral judgement is an inseparable part of judging the effectiveness of an outcome Not only does Givewell maintain an active blog, a Giving 101 section of its site, run free events in the Bay Area every few months and deliver well-curated email updates, but they keep updated copies of their Cost Effectiveness Models and Guide to Cost Effective Analysis available online for everyone to view.</description></item><item><title>concurrency in python</title><link>https://theleo.zone/posts/concurrency-in-python/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/posts/concurrency-in-python/</guid><description>Concurrency ! easy is Concurrency is of paramount importance in modern computing. It is a complex domain in itself, with major contributions from database development, machine learning, distributed application deployment, and academia.
Python requires a clear and simple concurrency framework as it is commonly used in high-compute settings like training neural networks. Matrix algebra has been made fast with NumPy and related tools, interfacing with C to get large performance improvements.</description></item><item><title>statistical bias</title><link>https://theleo.zone/posts/statistical-bias/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/posts/statistical-bias/</guid><description>Eat my spheres! You find yourself trapped in a room with Jigsaw, the villain from the Saw movies. There is a wood box of 100 spheres, some of them steel ball bearings and some of them gumballs. Jigsaw tells you that you can leave the room alive if you guess the number of steel ball bearings in the jar correctly. You can pull 10 random spheres out the 100 in the box as many times as you want, but each time you do, you have to eat all of them (yum!</description></item><item><title>linear regression</title><link>https://theleo.zone/posts/linear-regression/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/posts/linear-regression/</guid><description>Update 2019-10-25: Added MLE derivation and OLS $ \sigma^2 $
I have learned linear regression a number of times with varying of levels of detail. I&amp;rsquo;m making this document mostly as a reference for myself and any others who may be interested in the technique.
The concepts and explanations here come either from An Introduction to Statistical Learning (ISLR) or The Elements of Statistical Learning (ESLR). Other sources are listed at the bottom.</description></item><item><title>jupyter with docker</title><link>https://theleo.zone/posts/jupyter-with-docker/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theleo.zone/posts/jupyter-with-docker/</guid><description>I love docker. It makes environments:
portable across any machine subject to version control (retraceable and recoverable history) easily deployed and discarded with simple commands Jupyter is a great tool that allows for the creation of nice looking documents consisting of ordered code chunks with inline output. It is a fantastic way to get started with programming, clearly step through your workflow, and/or create stories and presentations out of your work.</description></item></channel></rss>